Th-This is...
（肆氏(しし)）こ… ここは…
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）まさか…
You don't mean...
My king!
（肆氏）大王さま！
Here we go.
（政(せい)）行くぞ
Open the door.
開けろ
（兵士）ははっ！
Yes, your majesty!
It's been quite some time...
久しぶりだな
Chengjiao!
成蟜(せいきょう)！
Stage of Strategy
（成蟜）
フフフッ… やっと来たか 嬴政(えいせい)
So you finally came, eh, Ying Zheng?
How dare you ignore my proposals and lock me up in this musty castle for so long.
（成蟜）俺の申し出を無視し続けて
よくも こんなカビくさい城に
長い間 閉じ込めてくれたな
Proposals?
申し出？
From Lord Chengjiao?
成蟜さまから？
I will cooperate in my campaign to defeat Lü Buwei,
“打倒 呂不韋(りょふい)に協力する
その代わり―”
and in exchange free everyone of the Chengjiao Faction confined to this castle.
“この城に幽閉されている
成蟜一派を全員 解放しろ”
それが 以前から
成蟜が俺に持ちかけてきていた話だ
That is the proposal that Chengjiao brought to me previously.
You mustn't, my king!
おやめください 大王さま
With all the power that faction still holds, releasing them is far too dangerous!
今でも大きな力を秘めている一派を
全員 解放するなど危険すぎます
（成蟜）黙れ 昌文君
（昌文君）ハッ…
Be quiet, Changwenjun.
Remember, I am the king's younger brother...
仮にも俺は大王の弟
しかも純粋な王族だ
and a pureblooded member of the royal family.
I have no grounds to be bound by your actions to begin with.
本来 貴様らに
行動を縛られる筋合いはない
My king...
大王さま…
Chengjiao...
成蟜
After having started a rebellion for the sake of your selfish ideals, I haven't the slightest intention of forgiving you.
独り善がりの理想のために―
反乱を起こしたお前を
許す気など 俺には毛頭ない
（政）だが
そんなことを言っていられぬほど
But now, the situation has gotten so dire that I do not have the luxury of saying such words.
事態は深刻で 急を要する
Now is my only chance to drive
a wedge into Lü Buwei's power.
猛威を振るう呂不韋の勢力に
クサビを打ち込む機会は今しかない
Lend me your strength, Chengjiao!
お前の力を俺に貸せ 嬴政！
Don't look down on me and give me orders.
俺を見下ろして命令するな
This is an equal deal with both of us seeking benefits.
これは 互いの
利益を追求する対等の取り引きだ
I just need you to be quiet and release us.
貴様は
黙って俺たちを解放すればいい
Now there's a familiar face...
（成蟜）懐かしい顔があるな
かつては 俺の命令で
嬴政の首を狙っていた貴様が―
You, someone who was once after Ying Zheng's head on my orders is now his close aide?
今では その嬴政の側近か…
立派な身分に
なったではないか 肆氏
You've gotten yourself a very comfortable seat, haven't you, Si Shi?
Hey, Changwenjun, rest easy.
おい 昌文君 安心しろ
I wouldn't just suddenly go back on our deal.
いきなり約束を反故(ほご)にしたりはせぬ
Even while he is not a pure-blooded member of the royal family,
純粋な王族ではない身でありながら
玉座に着いている嬴政を
俺は許せぬが
I cannot forgive Ying Zheng for being seated on the throne,
but I can't stand that man who rose to a seat of power from being a merchant from another kingdom even more!
それ以上に―
他国の商人から成り上がって
権力の座にある あの男のほうが
更に我慢ならぬ！
As a member of the royal family, it is my duty to bring order to the kingdom.
王国の秩序を正すのは
王族としての義務だ
Watch!
見ていろ
俺に従う王族たちの人脈を使って
Using my connections to the royal family members that obey me,
I will gather power that will allow
us to contend with that man.
あの男と互角に渡り合える勢力を
集めてやる
Do not misunderstand, Chengjiao.
（政）勘違いするな 成蟜
What I am requesting is not equal power.
俺が要求しているのは
互角の勢力などではない
It is power exceeding that of Lü Buwei!
呂不韋を上回る勢力だ！
真意の見えぬ連中でも かまわぬ
I do not care if it is with people
whose true motive I cannot see.
That much, I am willing to do.
その場かぎりの妥協も いとわぬ
Anyhow, in the next seven days
とにかく あと７日の間に―
できるかぎり多くの者を
こちらの味方につけろ！
gather as many people as possible onto our side!
Seven days?
あと７日の間？
What are you talking about?
どういうことだ？
Jie Shi, the one that conspired with you in your rebellion, is dead.
（政）かつて お前と結託して
起こした反乱で竭氏(けつし)が死んでから
左丞相(さじょうしょう)の席は空いたまま
So the seat of Left Chancellor is vacant...
そして こたび 右丞相の呂不韋が
相国(しょうこく)に上がったことで
And now, the Right Chancellor Lü Buwei has risen to the position of Prime Minister.
There are now two open chancellor seats.
丞相の席が２つ空いた
But Lü Buwei's confidants, Chanpingjun and Li Si are going to take those...
しかし そこには呂不韋の腹心
昌平君(しょうへいくん)と李斯(りし)が座ることに…
There are seven days until it is officially decided!
正式に決まるのは７日後だ
D-Do you mean...
まさか…
嬴政 貴様…
Ying Zheng... you bastard...
Changwenjun.
（政）昌文君
（昌文君）はっ！
Yes, my king?
The fact that you became a civil official in order to help me now has a very great meaning.
俺を助けるために
お前が文官へと転じてくれたことが
今こそ 大きな意味を持つ
My king...
大王さま…
We'll use Lü Buwei's reckless move of becoming Prime Minister against him.
（政）呂不韋が自ら
相国となった暴挙を逆手に取り
This time, we will seize power as well!
この機会に
俺たちも権力を取りに行くぞ！
But this loan will cost a great deal, Ying Zheng.
（成蟜）
しかし この貸しは高くつくぞ 嬴政
Nonsense. What I am lending is far more.
（政）ふざけるな
俺の貸しのほうが はるかに大きい
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）再び 物語の時間を戻す
We will go back in time in our story once again.
信(しん)たちは 韓(かん)軍に襲われていると
いう幻の小国 徐(じょ)に迫っていた
Xin and the others were drawing towards the illusory small country of Xu which was supposedly attacked by the Han Army.
Are we getting close?
（信）そろそろか？
お前が逃げてきた徐って国は
To the State of Xu that you ran away from?
（秀(しゅう)）はい…
Yes...
（尾平(びへい)）ひでえ…
This is terrible...
Everyone collapsed around here are children.
（澤圭(たくけい)）この辺りに倒れているのは
子供たちばかりです
What the hell happened here?
（沛浪(はいろう)）
一体 これは どういうことだ？
（貂(てん)）徐の人たちが
子供たちを逃がそうとしたんだ
The people of Xu... tried to allow the children to escape...
それを韓軍が見つけて…
And the Han Army found them.
So the only one that got away... was this kid?
（田有(でんゆう)）逃げきれたのは
このガキだけってことか
From the looks of things... it could be that even inside the castle...
（渕(えん)）
この様子では まさか城の中でも…
おっ母が… 中の砦(とりで)に おっ母が…
My mother... She's inside the fortress...
Mother!
おっ母！ おっ母！
おっ母！
（轟音）
貂 あの音は？
Diao, what's that sound?
Most likely, the Han Army is trying to break down a door inside the fortress.
恐らく 韓軍が中の砦の扉を
打ち破ろうとしている音だ
…てことは まだ間に合うな？
So you're saying...
we can still make it?
（貂）ああ
（信）作戦は？
Yeah!
What's our plan?!
あの城の大きさから考えると
韓軍の兵は2,000人程度
Basing off the size of that castle...
There are at least 2,000 Han Army soldiers.
We're at a disadvantage in terms of numbers,
数の上では劣勢だが
奇襲をかければ
こっちにも勝ち目はある
but with a surprise attack we have a chance at victory!
敵の虚を突いて
一気に たたきつぶすんだ
If we strike the enemy where they're unguarded, we can crush them in one attack!
（信）了解！
Got it!
Xiu, hold on.
秀 待ってろ
お前の母ちゃんたちは
絶対 助けてやる！
We'll save your mom and the others no matter what it takes!
Mister...
（秀）おにいちゃん…
Okay, let's do this, you bastards!
よっしゃ！ いくぞ てめえら！
Hurry and get it open!
（馬関(ばかん)）さっさと開けろ！
Once we've got that gate open, all that's left is to finish off the lot inside.
（馬関）その門さえ開ければ
あとは 中の連中を片づけるだけだ
It's no good, Elder!
（徐の男性Ａ）
ダメです 長老さま！
We can't hold out any longer!
もうこれ以上
持ちこたえられません！
（女性１）長老！
（女性２）長老さま！
Elder!
Great Elder!
Is this the end?
ここまでか…
（徐の男性Ａ）長老さま！
Elder!
The Han Army's attack stopped...
韓軍の攻撃が止まりました！
Something odd is going on outside!
外の様子が… 変です！
（信）ハアッ！ ハアッ！
Mounted unit, charge!
（信）騎馬隊 突っ込めー！
（車輪兵Ａ）
馬関さま！ 秦国(しんこく)の軍が…
The Qin Army's...
飛信(ひしん)隊が現れました！
Feixin Unit has appeared!
うらぁ！
Xin
（楚水(そすい)）ンンッ…
（２人）ハアーッ！
（沛浪･去亥(きょがい)）ハアーッ！
（吹き飛ぶ音）
ウワーッ！
（田永(でんえい)･竜有(りゅうゆう)）ハアーッ！
オリャー！
（慶(けい)･昂(こう)）ヤーッ！
（魯延(ろえん)）アッ… アッ…
（斬る音）
（韓兵）ウワッ！
（松左(しょうさ)）フフッ…
（飛信隊兵）ウワッ！
（松左）ハッ…
調子に乗るなよ
秦国の山猿どもが！
Don't get cocky, you State of Qin monkeys!
廉頗(れんぱ)四天王のひとり 輪虎(りんこ)を
討ったとかいう―
Where's the Feixin Unit Captain, Xin? The one they say took down Lun Hu, one of Lian Po's Four Heavenly Kings.
飛信隊の隊長は どこだ？
I, 2000-Man General of the Han Army, the great Ma Guan will be your opponent!
韓軍二千人将 馬関さまが
相手になってやるぞ！
So he's the general, huh?
あいつが大将か…
Out of the way, guys!
どいてろ てめえら！
そいつは俺がやる！
I'll take him on!
信 気をつけろ！
そいつ かなりの使い手だ！
Xin, be careful!
That guy's pretty good!
I know!
分かってらぁ！
Vice Captain Chu Shui, Lord Xin is going to fight alone...
（田孝(でんこう)）
楚水副長！ 信どのが１人で…
大丈夫だ
It's all right.
Don't get conceited because of one or two flukes, kid!
１度や２度のマグレで
いい気になるなよ 小僧が！
（楚水）信どのは
輪虎との戦いを経験して以来…
Ever since Lord Xin went through his battle with Lun Hu...
ちょこざいな！
Don't get smart!
His skill at mounted battle has gotten remarkably better!
（楚水）馬を御しての戦いが
格段に うまくなった
What?!
なにぃ！
うらぁ！
Captain Ma Guan was...
（韓兵１）馬関隊長が…
（韓兵２）たった ひと太刀で…
In just one strike...
韓軍の兵士ども！ よ～く聞け！
Han Army soldiers!
Listen up!
抵抗もしねえ子供たちまで
殺しやがって…
If you pieces of shit are gonna kill kids that can't even defend themselves...
てめえらみてえなクズどもは―
Then Xin of the Feixin Unit...
will not show you any mercy!
この飛信隊の信が許さねえ！
（韓兵）に… 逃げろー！
（韓兵）退却だー！
R-Run!
Retreat!
おっ母！
（母親）秀！ 秀！
Mother!
Xiu! Xiu! I'm so glad... So glad you're all right...
良かった… 良かった 無事で…
（秀）おっ母！ おっ母！
Mother! Mother!
Are you Xin of the Feixin Unit?
（長老）飛信隊の信どのですな？
（信･貂）うん？
A long time ago, you took the head of General Feng Ji in a war with the State of Zhao.
かつて
趙国(ちょうこく)との戦で 馮忌(ふうき)将軍の首を取り
せんだっての魏国(ぎこく)との戦では
あの輪虎将軍を討ち取った
And recently, you slew that man General Lun Hu in a war with the State of Wei.
We've already heard of you, brave young Thousand-Man General from the State of Qin.
秦国の若き千人将の武勇は
既に聞き及んでおります
そして こたびは
この徐の国の危機を救ってくださり
And now, you have saved our State of Xu from danger.
お礼の申しようもございませぬ
I do not know how to express my thanks.
So this one little castle is really a country?
へえ！ 本当に
この小さな城１つだけで国なのか？
You guys did well to survive this long in a place right on state borders where there's nonstop war.
国境が入り組んでいて
争いが絶えない こんな場所で
よく今まで無事で…
はい… この徐の国が
存在し続けてこられたのには―
Yes. There is a reason that this State of Xu has survived for so long.
理由があります
Wei
Zhao
Chu
Xu
徐は魏 趙 楚(そ)の３国から
庇護(ひご)を受けているのです
Xu receives protection from the three states of Wei, Zhao, and Chu.
えっ？ ３国から庇護を…
Protection from three states?
Why is that?
それって どういう…
In this warring world, knowing the state of other kingdoms is vital.
この戦乱の世では―
他国の動静を知ることが
何よりも重要であり
If there is a place where one can safely obtain that information,
その情報を
安全に入手できる場所があるならば
that place becomes a precious commodity.
そこは大変 重宝されるのです
In other words, this country tells each of those three countries information about their enemy countries
つまり この国は―
３国に
それぞれ敵対する国の情報を教えて
and in exchange, they offer you protection.
その代わりに
安全を保障されている
In other words, you make your livelihood by selling information?
言い換えれば
情報の横流しを生業(なりわい)にしていると…
I have no excuse.
（長老）弁明は いたしませぬ
これは 弱い者が弱いなりに―
This is a weak method that the weak use in order to survive in a warring world.
戦乱の世を
生き延びるためのすべですから
The area around this State of Xu is full of treacherous rocky mountains and a huge sea of trees.
この徐と周辺の地は 険しい岩山と
広大な樹海に囲まれていて
So it has the unique condition of being extremely difficult for outsiders to find.
他国の人間が発見することは
極めて難しいという―
特殊な条件を備えています
In actuality, even in Wei, Zhao, and Chu,
実際 魏 趙 楚の３国でも―
only the most important people like the Prime Ministers know of Xu's existence.
徐の存在は 宰相などの
最重要人物しか知りません
And because of that, the spies sent on secret missions from the major figures of those kingdoms
だからこそ 徐は―
それらの最重要人物から
密命を受けた諜報員たちが―
meet behind closed doors and bargain.
秘密裏に交流し
駆け引きを行う―
謀略の舞台としても
存在し続けているのです
We have long existed as the "stage of strategy".
ちょっと待て…
Hold on a minute...
It's true that gathering information on enemy countries is the most vital thing there is in an era of warring states,
確かに 国同士の争いでは―
敵国に関する情報を集めることが
何よりも重要だし
and the strategies orienting around that are indispensable.
それに基づいて
謀略を巡らせることが不可欠だ
秦国は こういう場を
ちゃんと持っているのか？
Does the State of Qin have a hand in this place?
If we don't...
もし持っていないとしたら…
By the way, what was with that Han Army from before?
ところで
さっきの韓軍は何だったんだ？
Shouldn't Han not know about this place?
韓のヤツらは この国のこと
知らないはずじゃなかったのか？
Not long ago, a Han unit wandered into the sea of trees
少し前
韓の部隊が樹海に迷い込んで
and learned of Xu by coincidence.
偶然 この徐の存在を
知ってしまったのです
Han demanded that we manipulate our information in order to send those three kingdoms into disorder.
韓は ３国が混乱するように
情報を操作しろと要求してきました
We refused purely because of our neutral position.
（長老）我々は あくまでも
中立の立場ゆえ 断ったのですが…
その結果が今の状況というわけです
But the result was what you see before you.
Please, take this.
（長老）
これを持っていってくだされ
It is a map of this area.
この辺り一帯の地図です
あなた方が
目指している東金城(とうきんじょう)への道も―
It contains a path to the Dongjin Castle you see as well.
書き込んでおきました
国を救っていただいて―
Forgive me for being able to offer nothing more to express my gratitude for saving our country.
こんなお礼しかできないことを
お許しくだされ
Don't sweat it, gramps.
気にすんな じいさん
別に 礼なんて期待してなかったし
I wasn't really expecting any kinda thanks.
それに 地図は ありがてえよ
俺ら 持ってなかったから
And we're real thankful for the map.
We didn't have one.
Will you be all right without us?
俺たちが いなくなって大丈夫か？
また韓軍が攻めてきたら…
What if the Han Army attacks again?
Because of the threat you posed with your bravery earlier, Lord Xin,
先ほどの信どのの
武勇と威嚇が効いておりますゆえ
当分は攻めてこないでしょう
I don't think we will have any attacks for some time.
それに いざとなれば
３国に助けを求めます
And if necessary, we can request help from the three kingdoms.
さすれば 彼らも
手をこまねいてはおりますまい
I doubt they could just stand back and watch us be attacked.
Xu is a precious information gathering resource for them.
彼らにとって 徐は
大切な情報の収集場所なのですから
So this kingdom's weapon is information, huh?
情報が この国の武器ってわけか…
ヘヘッ… 世の中
いろんな戦い方があるんだな
I guess there are lots of ways to fight out there.
Okay, our target is Dongjin Castle, let's go!
よし！
東金城を目指して出発するぞ！
（秀）おにいちゃん！
（信）うん？
Mister!
Oh, it's you, Xiu!
おお 秀か！
どうだ？ ケガは　大丈夫か？
How are your injuries? Are you okay?
Yeah, but they really hurt.
でも すごく痛い
（信）ハハハハッ！
我慢しろ　名誉の傷だ！
Hang in there!
Those are honorable wounds!
Your efforts saved this kingdom!
お前の頑張りが
この国を救ったんだからよ
Thank you, mister!
（秀）ありがとう おにいちゃん！
絶対 絶対 おにいちゃんのこと
忘れないから！
I'll never, ever forget you!
おう！
俺も お前のこと絶対 忘れねえぞ！
Okay! I'll never forget you, either!
So long!
じゃあな！
すさまじく精密な地図だ
This sure is a precise map...
According to this map, if we'd proceeded forward without going to Xu,
この地図によると 徐に行かずに
まっすぐ進んでいたら―
we would've come across Wei and Zhao garrisons.
魏国と趙国の
駐屯軍に出くわしていた
遠回りしたようでも
結果的に東金城には早く着くと
So even though we took a detour, we'll end up getting to Dongjin Castle faster.
ハハハハッ！ やっぱり
人助けは しとくもんだなぁ…
I knew helping people was a good thing!
That's Shi's stone whistle!
（去亥）石(せき)の石笛だ！
（沛浪）敵を発見した合図だぞ
That signal means he's spotted an enemy!
All troops, halt!
全軍 停止！
That's odd...
おかしいな… 長老は この道に
敵は いないって言ってたのに
The elder said there were no enemies on this path.
結構いるな…
（貂）3,000は いる
There sure are a lot of 'em.
There's 3,000.
Just what state are they from?
一体 どこの国のヤツらだ？
旗を下ろしているから分からないな
I can't tell without any flags up.
（貂）そもそも
彼らは どうして ここにいるんだ？
Why are they here in the first place?
The Xu elder said that even in Wei, Zhao, and Chu,
この辺りの道は
魏 趙 楚の３国でも―
宰相などの最重要人物しか
知らないって―
this place isn't supposed to be known to anyone except people like Prime Ministers.
徐の長老が言ってたのに
つまり どっかの国の偉(えれ)えヤツの
命令で来たってことか？
In other words, they came here on the orders of some kingdom's big-wig?
Look.
（石）見ろ
Man, that's one huge carriage.
（信）オオッ！
でっけえ馬車が出てきやがったぜ
ひょっとして
偉えヤツが自分でノコノコ―
Do ya think the big-wig just strolled out here himself?
こんなとこまで
やって来やがったのかな？
オッ… 馬車が止まった！
Oh, it stopped!
The general's comin' out.
大将が出てくんぞ
Well, not like I'll know who he is by sight, though...
まあ 姿を見せたところで
どこの誰だって話だけどな…
李牧(りぼく)！
Li Mu!
カイネ！
（石）隊長 バレるぞ
Kaine!
Captain, we'll be seen.
What's going on?
どういうことだ？
What's that Li Mu bastard doing at a place like this?!
李牧の野郎が こんなとこで…
何をしてやがるんだ？
Preview
A New Legend
End